<rss xmlns:a10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title /><link>http://nrez.github.io/feed.xml</link><description /><item><guid isPermaLink="true">http://nrez.github.io/2014/02/cracking-the-cocoon/</guid><link>http://nrez.github.io/2014/02/cracking-the-cocoon/</link><title>CRACKING THE COCOON</title><description>&lt;p&gt;Each life has a time comes we need to get out of something; something like a multitude of layers, woven by you. 
Under it we are protected; away from everything, unscathed, solely in solitude. 
Staying shielded inside does make it your comfort zone and it is extremely tough to get out. 
Many choose not to; to die within, while a handful rip it up, to face the lustrous world. &lt;/p&gt;

</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 18:30:00 Z</pubDate><a10:updated>2014-01-31T18:30:00Z</a10:updated><a10:content type="text">&lt;p&gt;Each life has a time comes we need to get out of something; something like a multitude of layers, woven by you. 
Under it we are protected; away from everything, unscathed, solely in solitude. 
Staying shielded inside does make it your comfort zone and it is extremely tough to get out. 
Many choose not to; to die within, while a handful rip it up, to face the lustrous world. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a silly kid, the life cycle of the moth amused me a lot and still does much more than the software life cycle. 
Cocoon takes the fat and sluggish caterpillar as input and gives a beautifully dynamic creature, HOW? 
Stupidly Intelligent Me: “A moth and caterpillar are different as the caterpillar dies after giving birth to the moth.” 
People: “Is this kid really crazy? Or just trying to be?” 
It persisted until a science teacher showed the path to cognition, with diagrams of the actual process. 
This fascinated me even further, to see how this creature planned its life, depicting nature as the best teacher. 
I was vaguely correct, "&lt;em&gt;The fat and sluggish caterpillar does die, giving birth to the beautifully dynamic moth&lt;/em&gt;".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But where are humans going man? The majority can’t fight to get out of their luring comfort zone to explore the brilliance outside. 
Think about the moth’s thoughts inside the cocoon post mutating: “Ok so, looks like we’re done here… I’ve got wings without instruction manuals. 
If I leave, there are hardships, harsh weather, daily night-shifts, etc. Plus the fancy color would make an easy prey.&lt;br /&gt;
So stay here? Forever..? Naah; not cool… This place is surely safe and I’ve attachments here. 
But I’m born to fly free, fall, rise and stay fit to survive everything, till death. I’m a moth, not a sloth and I’d prefer dying rather than shying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once mature, we tend to take smaller steps, while daunted to fly. 
Yes, I know we may fall flat, lose our limbs or might as well die, but then is this living? 
Why not make myself count and live life? We have countless colors to show, dynamic wings to fly high and low and elegance that can aspire countless. 
So… &lt;strong&gt;COME OUT&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Deep deep down within my heart...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Do I yearn to go back and start..?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Plough and nurture all those ways...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Where I just passed with utter laze...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Could that have been far better or worse..?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;This shrub of my life; did I decently nurse..?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Arising over this cliff, I think it's now or never...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I'll either fly immensely high or fall beneath forever...&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It is mandatory to travel; but has everything been packed..?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Coz life is all about moving further and then never going back...&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moth"&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Moth&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="http://animalsunlimited.co.uk/what-is-the-difference-between-a-cocoon-a-chrysalis-and-a-pupa/"&gt;http://animalsunlimited.co.uk/what-is-the-difference-between-a-cocoon-a-chrysalis-and-a-pupa/&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--excerpt--&gt;
</a10:content></item></channel></rss>